Preliminary Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. Media Center Audio-Visual Collection, 1980s-2000s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. Media Center Audio-Visual collection 1980s-2000s
J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office.
27.3 linear feet Extent: 536 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00734
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. Media Center Audio-Visual Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001-2002.
Historical Note
The J. Walter Thompson Company was founded in New York, N.Y., in 1864, and is one of the world's largest advertising agencies.
Collection Overview
Collection is comprised primarily of 121 audio cassette tapes of radio commercials produced for various clients by JWT San Francisco ([1980s-early 1990s]) and collected by the Media Center. Formerly called the Creative Library, the Center makes available to JWT staff the creative products of various JWT offices. Also includes 6 CD-ROMs of print ads from JWT offices in Asia Pacific Region (1998-1999); 22 color slides of print ads from JWT Argentina (1997-1998); and 1 DAT of 8 radio spots for Lipton Ice Tea and monthly calendars, both produced by the New York Office (2000-2001). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising and Marketing History.
The addition (2002-0203; 117 items, 5.0 linear feet) consists largely of tapes of radio commercials for a variety of JWT clients and brands, especially Eastman Kodak, Lipton, Trident, and Weight Watchers. Formats include VHS, U-Matic, and D-2 videotapes; DAT and digital audio mastering tapes; computer disks; and 8mm data storage cartridges. Also includes VHS copies of various films and TV shows.
The addition (2003-0231; 80 items, 5.5 linear feet) consists largely of video tapes of various commercials from JWT international offices, including ads for Listering, Nestle, Siemans, and Kellogg products, and possibly the only existing cpy of a Kodak "Wedding" ad. Also contains one audio CD and a small number of print ads.
The addition (2003-0232; 175 items, 15 linear feet) consists largely of video tapes of various commercials from JWT international offices, especially London, Asia and Latin America. Also includes Video Strategies USA tapes of ads that premiered 1981-1983, Worldwide Creative Council, and other spots.
Subject Headings
J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office; J. Walter Thompson Company. San Francisco Office; J. Walter Thompson Company. Asia-Pacific Region; J. Walter Thompson Company. Argentina Office; Eastman Kodak Company; Thomas J. Lipton, Inc.; Weight Watchers International; Radio advertising; Television advertising; Advertising -- Asia; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- Pacific Area; Audiocassettes; Color slides; Machine-readable records; Videocassettes; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2002-0022
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - 54 Audiocassettes of radio commercials for various clients produced by JWT San Francisco Office, [1980s-early 1990s] (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - 54 Audiocassettes of radio commercials for various clients produced by JWT San Francisco Office, [1980s-early 1990s] (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - 13 Audiocassettes of radio commercials for various clients produced by JWT San Francisco Office, [1980s-early 1990s] (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - 6 CD-ROMs of print ads for various clients produced by JWT Asia-Pacific, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
    - 1 DAT of 8 radio spots for Lipton Ice Tea produced by JWT New York, 2001 (Box 4)
    - 11 color slides of print ads for various clients produced by JWT Argentina, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Monthly calendars produced by public relations, JWT New York, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
- Accession 2002-0203
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Weekly Reels, 2001 (Box 1)
    - NY Times Best '98 (Box 1)
    - Allen's Picks: 1998 Creative Standards (Box 1)
    - JWT Television Commercials 1998 (Box 1)
    - Creative Standards 1998 (Box 1)
      Other TV commercials from master reel that were not used for WPP board reel.
    - Muppet Meetings Films (Box 1)
      (Humorous meeting openings), excellent quality.
    - Various Ford Weekly Comp. Reels (Box 1)
      These are reels made by the FDAF library at JWT Detroit of all of the new Ford spots that broke, and sometimes of competitor spots.
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Weekly reels, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
    - Bye-Bye Babushka, directed by Rebecca Feig, Persistence of Vision Films (Box 2)
    - Shooting Back: Photography by Homeless Children, 30-minute documentary by Robin Smith, Washington Project for the Arts and Video Fund (Box 2)
    - Hate, motion picture directed by Matthieu Kassovitz (Box 2)
    - AAAA: Fifty Years of Free TV (Box 2)
    - AAAA: Self Regulation 1/1984 (Box 2)
    - Kellogg Nutrigrain Historical Reel (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - The Addams Family (Box 3)
    - The Burns and Allen Show (3 tapes) (Box 3)
    - The Dick Van Dyke Show: "All About Laura" (Box 3)
    - Summer of '42, motion picture directed by Robert Mulligan (Box 3)
    - You Bet Your Life (3 copies) (Box 3)
      Includes original commercials sponsored by Desoto Plymouth.
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Radio commercials (Box 4)
      Includes spots for Bailey's Irish Creme, IPlanet.com, Imovec, Kodak, Lipton, Ortho, Society Bank, Trident, and Weight Watchers.
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Radio commercials (Box 5)
      Includes spots for Lipton, Listerine, and Rolaids.
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Radio commercials (Box 6)
      Includes spots for Lipton and Weight Watchers.
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - Radio commercials (Box 7)
      Includes spots for IPlanet.com, Kodak, Lipton, Rolaids, Trident, and Weight Watchers.
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - Radio commercials (Box 8)
      Includes spots for Ford, Kodak, and Lipton.
- Accession 2003-0231
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - JWT Refueling :60, :45, :30, The Making of Refuelling 6:00, 10:00, 1998 Jan. (Box 1)
    - JWT Thai Airlines Total Branding, 1998 (Box 1)
    - JWT Shanghai Nike, 1998? (Box 1)
      Includes Ball Handler :15, Sharp Shooter :15, and Blocking :15.
    - JWT Czech Republic (Box 1)
      Includes Total Branding, 1997 June
    - JWT Jaguar XK8 (Box 1)
      Includes Total Branding-UK Europe 1997 July
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Old Friends, KPN Telecom, 1999 Jan. 19 (Box 2)
    - DJ NY, Heineken (Box 2)
    - Shanghai, Heineken (Box 2)
    - Knieval, Zilveren Kruis (Box 2)
    - HIJ IS AF, BMW (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Radio 3 FM (Box 3)
      Includes Raggende Mannen, Skik, and Nilsson.
    - Tolerance Unlimited (Box 3)
    - Teddybear, KPN Telecom (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Radio 3 FM (Box 4)
      Includes RandB;, Dulfer, and Alternatief
    - Nestle Rowntree, Kit Kat, UK TV and Press, 1999 Mar. 1 (Box 4)
    - PPGH JWT Amsterdam (Box 4)
      Includes Nestle Holland, Lion, and Woman on Couch
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Kodak, Wedding, :45 (Box 5)
      [May be only existing copy of this commercial.]
    - Best of 3rd Quarter 1998, Sao Paulo, Brazil (Box 5)
    - JWT Argentina, Comerciales 1998 (Box 5)
    - JWT Best of Latin America, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
    - JWT Best of Latin America, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - JWT Best of Latin America, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
    - 1997 Creative Standards Reel (Box 6)
    - Comerciales JWTA en Ingles (Box 6)
    - JWT Argentina Subtitled Commercials (Box 6)
    - Reel Comerciales MiniPhone (Box 6)
    - Comerciales JWT 1998 (Box 6)
    - Peru 1998 (Box 6)
    - Toronto 1998, Various Creative (Box 6)
      Includes Halls/Philly/K.D. Spaghetti
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - Toronto Office, 1996 Jan. (Box 7)
    - JWT Toronto Office (Box 7)
    - Northern Telecom, 1994 Nov. 14 (Box 7)
    - JWT Toronto Reel, 1995 July 7 (Box 7)
    - JWT Toronto, 1994 Jan. 19 (Box 7)
    - J. Walter Thompson Co. Ltd.: Kellogg-Various (Box 7)
    - JWT Creative Dept. Select Spots (Box 7)
    - JWT Toronto Creative Compilation Reel (Box 7)
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - Kraft Canada, NABOB Coffee Company-Various (Box 8)
    - 1st Trimester 1995 Advertising, Latin America 1995 July 18 (Box 8)
    - JWT Argentina 1998 (Box 8)
    - JWT Toronto, Listerine (Box 8)
      Includes Stepping Out.
    - Rotella T Australia (Box 8)
  - Contents of Box 9: (Box 9)
    - Asia-Pacific 1999 1st Quarter Show Reel, 1999 Apr. 1,J. Walter Thompson Company (Box 9)
    - JWT Europe Reel, 1999 Aug. (Box 9)
    - Television Commercials, JWT London Presentation, 1999 Oct. 29 (Box 9)
    - Larry and Allen's Best Picks, Creative Standards, 1998 Feb. (Box 9)
    - J. Walter Thompson, North America, 1998 Mar. 17 (Box 9)
    - JWT Worldwide New Creative Long Reel, Fourth Quarter 1998 (Box 9)
  - Contents of Box 10: (Box 10)
    - JWT Sydney Agency TVC (Box 10)
      Includes Stitches, :30, and This is PAL.
    - JWT Toronto, Clorets, Breath Patrol (Box 10)
    - Siemens SL10 (Box 10)
      Includes Vanessa Mae :40 and :10, and Jean Paul Gaultier :40 and :10.
    - Siemens C25 9 Versionen, CA 3 MIN 1999 Juni 22 (Box 10)
    - Siemens C25 International Products Launch 1999, 7 Min 25 Sec., 1999 Juli 23 (Box 10)
  - Contents of Box 11: (Box 11)
    - JWT Siemens Products, Tape 1, 1999 Juli 26 (Box 11)
    - JWT Siemens Products, Tape 2, 1999 Juli 26 (Box 11)
    - NY Times Best and Worst, 1998 (Box 11)
    - Best Spots of 1997 and Worst Spots of 1997 (Box 11)
    - International Spots Non-JWT (Box 11)
  - Contents of Box 12: (Box 12)
    - JWT/Detroit (RAF) Weekly Reels (Box 12)
      Includes 5/6, 5/13, 5/20, 5/28, 6/03, 6/10, and 6/17.
    - JWT/Detroit (RAF) Weekly Reels (Box 12)
      Includes 3/04/02, 3/11/02, 3/18/02, 3/25/02, 4/1/02, 4/8/02, 4/22/02, and 4/29/02.
    - JWT/Detroit (RAF) Weekly Reel (Box 12)
      Includes 1/7/02, 1/21/02, 1/28/02, and 2/4/02.
    - Audio CD, "Passion North America" [goes with booklet in OS folder 1] (Box 12)
  - Contents of Oversize Folder 1: (Opaperfolder 1)
    - Non-Video Items (Opaperfolder 1)
      Includes ads for folate and a booklet on Passion North America.
- Accession 2003-0232
  [Accession is restricted. Internal, unpublished records 15 years old or less are closed to all researchers except former JWT employees or by permission of the Director of the Hartman Center.]
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Paris, Rogale (Box 1)
    - JWT-Tokyo, Creative Review 2000, 2nd Quarter (Box 1)
    - Hong Kong 2nd Quarter Submission 2000 (Box 1)
    - JWT/Sydney (Box 1)
      Includes Nestle, Kit Kat, and Concrete Garden.
    - JWT/Sydney (2000) (Box 1)
      Includes Nestle, Kit Kat, and Speed Cop.
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - JWT/Australia (Box 2)
      Includes Nestle, Kit Kat, and Baby Mop.
    - JWT/Tokyo, 2000 Creative Standard Review, 1st Quarter (Box 2)
    - JWT/Sydney: Mission Australia, Lucky Country/Brand Launch (Box 2)
    - JWT/Sydney (Box 2)
      Includes Kimberly-Clark, Kleenex, and Pub.
    - London, Autumn Showreel (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - JWT Mexico Ads Compliation, Torr, 2000 June 7 (Box 3)
    - Bangkok Hughes, Various Asia Pacific (Box 3)
    - Reel for Catie Marshall (Box 3)
      Includes Kraft Dairylea Dunkers and Nestle Rowntree Kit Kat, 1999 Apr. 29
    - Paris, Rogale (Box 3)
      Includes Siemens' Pool.
    - JWT-Latin America Reel, 2000 Mar. (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - JWT- The Wave (Box 4)
    - JWT-Lima: TV Commercials of Cuquena (Box 4)
    - JWT Latin America: Patricia Bonta (Box 4)
    - Bombay: Godre, Photofridge-45 seconds (Box 4)
    - 2nd Quarter Creative Work, Bombay (Box 4)
    - JWT Vietnam (Box 4)
    - Vietnam (Box 4)
    - Manila (Box 4)
    - JWT (Box 4)
      Includes Funeral, Armistice Movie, and Alien Lobster Agency
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - JWT Bangkok-Hughes (Box 5)
    - JWT Venezuela Reel, 2000 Apr. (Box 5)
    - Colombia: Portatil, Heroes de Turno (Box 5)
    - Sequiera (Box 5)
    - JWT Rio de Janeiro (Box 5)
    - Onitelecom Internet, Slow :30 (Box 5)
    - Elida Pond's Sedal Control (Box 5)
    - Reel Creative Work, Harry Kramp, Worldwide Creative Council 2000, 2000 June 5 (Box 5)
    - JWT, Andrew Thompson Showreel (Box 5)
    - Argentina Q2 Reel (Box 5)
    - Asia Pacific 2nd Quarter 2000 (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - JWT-Taipei, 2nd Quarter (Box 6)
    - Thompson Nepal TVC (Box 6)
      Includes OK Soap, Wheel Powerons, Himal Magazine.
    - Fair and Lovely- I Want the Best Campaign with Subtitles (Nepal) (Box 6)
    - JWT New York: WWC 2000 (Box 6)
      Includes Vietnam, Sydney, and PPGH/Amsterdam.
    - Vietnam, 2000 Apr.-June (Box 6)
    - Shanghai, Sheung Yan Lo (Box 6)
      Includes Pepsi, Siemens, and Nike.
    - Sao Paolo: Misterio/Jornalista (Legendado) (Box 6)
    - Shelbourne (Box 6)
    - Lisbon (Box 6)
      Includes Governmental Road, Accident Prevention, Yunk Dealer, and Lithano Cheese-Cheese Little Mouse.
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - Paris (Box 7)
      Includes Montage Agency Michel Rogale and Paris After Eight Dinner Party (Various Ads).
    - 2nd Quarter Europe, Middle East (Box 7)
    - JWT London (Box 7)
    - Agency Film (Box 7)
    - Toronto (Box 7)
      Includes Kraft and Kemp.
    - Ford, Herald Sun, and The Weekly Times (Box 7)
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - Sydney (Box 8)
    - Tape 1, Sequeira (Box 8)
      Includes BPI Bank Personal Credit, Kitchen, Computer, and Toll.
    - Tape 2, Sequeira (Box 8)
      Includes Onitelecom, Internet, and Slow.
    - Lisbon (Box 8)
    - CDs
      - JWT Spring 2000 Reel, Quicktime and AVI formats (Box 8)
      - WWCE Shatlist (?) MPEG, 2000 (Box 8)
      - CJ WPP Reel MPEG (Box 8)
      - Panchera (Box 8)
      - JWT: World Wide Creative Council Meeting, London (Box 8)
      - Asia-Pacific 1999 Print Ads JPEG Slide Show, 2000 Jan. 7 (Box 8)
      - Deja Vu (Box 8)
      - European Creative League (Box 8)
      - 2nd Quarter 2000 (Box 8)
      - JWT Tokyo Creative Standard Review 2000 2nd Quarter, Best Print, Best TTB (Box 8)
      - Smirnoff Posters, Baltik 2000 June 26 (Box 8)
      - Ritz 2001 Apr. 23, 6 JPEGS (Box 8)
  - Contents of Box 9: (Box 9)
    - Asia Pacific 1998 1st-4th Quarter Reels (Box 9)
    - Shell, Tim Davis Presentation 2001 Apr. 18 (Box 9)
  - Contents of Box 10: (Box 10)
    - Asia/Pacific 1st Quarter Review Tapes 1-2 (Box 10)
    - Unilever Advertising for HPC Meeting, 2001 Apr. 23 (Box 10)
    - Tokyo Creative Standards, 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Contents of Box 11: (Box 11)
    - Summer Showreel 2000 (Box 11)
    - WWCC London, Jan. 22-23 (Box 11)
      Includes Benchmark, submissions 1-94.
    - WWCC London, Jan. 22-23 (Box 11)
      Includes Benchmark, submissions 95 and 96.
    - Golf Digest Urinal 15 inch TVC, 2000 Nov. (Box 11)
    - WWCC 2000 Q3-Global Tape (2 tapes) (Box 11)
    - Nestle (Box 11)
    - JWT 1 Korea (Box 11)
    - [Miscellaneous Files] (Box 11)
  - Contents of Box 12: (Box 12)
    - 1:45 Credo Intro (Box 12)
    - Exco Reel, June 2000, Cannes (Box 12)
    - Hong Kong (Box 12)
    - Global Agency Network Reel 2000 (2 tapes) (Box 12)
    - JWT European-New Creative Work EXCO 2000 Feb., NTSC (Box 12)
    - Reel Ford Creative Regional (Box 12)
  - Contents of Box 13: (Box 13)
    - World Wide Creative Council 2000, Europe Part 1 (Box 13)
    - World Wide Creative Council 2000, Europ Part 2 and Middle East (Box 13)
    - Worldwide Reel 1st Quarter (2 tapes) (Box 13)
    - Worldwide Creative Council 2000, Canada and Latin America (Box 13)
    - Worldwide Creative Council 2000, Asia Pacific (Box 13)
    - Worldwide Reel 1st Quarter Beta (2 tapes) (Box 13)
    - JWT Worldwide, Q2 2000 (Box 13)
    - Worldwide Reel Q2, 2000 (Box 13)
  - Contents of Box 14: (Box 14)
    - Video Strategies USA 1981 Dec., Section 1: Amusement, Leisure, and Travel (Box 14)
    - Video Strategies USA 1981 Dec., Section 2: Appliances and Home Entertainment (Parts 1 and 2) (Box 14)
    - Video Strategies USA 1981 Dec., Section 3: Automotive (Parts 1 and 2) (Box 14)
  - Contents of Box 15: (Box 15)
    - Video Strategies USA 1981 Dec., Section 4: Beverages (Parts 1 and 2) (Box 15)
    - Video Strategies USA 1981 Dec. Section 5: Cosmetics and Personal Hygiene (Part 1) (Box 15)
    - Video Strategies USA 1981 Dec., Section 6: Financial and Business Services (Box 15)
    - Video Strategies USA 1981 Dec., Section 7: Food (Parts 1 and 2) (Box 15)
  - Contents of Box 16: (Box 16)
    - Video Strategies USA 1981 Dec.,Section 8: Food Preparation, Snack Food, and Pet Food (Parts 1 and 2) (Box 16)
    - Video Strategies USA 1981 Dec., Section 9: Laundry and Paper Products (Parts 1 and 2) (Box 16)
    - Video Strategies USA 1981 Dec., Section 10: Medicines (Box 16)
  - Contents of Box 17: (Box 17)
    - Video Strategies USA, 1981 Dec., Section 11: Retail and Apparel (Parts 1 and 2) (Box 17)
    - Video Strategies USA, 1981 Dec., Section 12: Toys and Games (Box 17)
    - Greece Police Force Grand Mother, :30 (Box 17)
    - Austrian Airlines, It flies, it flies... TVC 40-inch ULB/NISC 1998 Dec. 2 (Box 17)
  - Contents of Box 18: (Box 18)
    - Video Strategies, 12/1981 (Box 18)
  - Contents of Box 19: (Box 19)
    - JWT London Showreel, 1998 May 13 (Box 19)
    - Kronung, Heritage, London 1997 Jan. (Box 19)
    - J. Walter Thompson Paris, 1998 Oct. 9 (Box 19)
      Includes Nestle- Scout/Girl Guides and Liptonic- Cantona, all with translations.
    - Video Strategies USA Guide Booklet, 1981 Dec. (Box 19)
  - Contents of Box 20: (Box 20)
    - JWT International Reel 1989 (Box 20)
    - JWT Europe Showreel 1993 Nov. (Box 20)
    - Video Strategies: Amusements, Leisure, and Travel (Section 1, Parts 1 and 2), 1983 Jan. (Box 20)
    - Video Strategies (Sections 2-5), 1983 Jan. (Box 20)
    - Video Strategies: Financial and Business Services, 1983 Jan. (Box 20)
    - Video Strategies (Sections 7-12), 1983 Jan. (Box 20)
    - Video Strategies: Amusements, Leisure and Travel, 1983 Feb. (Box 20)
    - Video Strategies (Sections 2-12), 1983 Feb. (Box 20)
  - Contents of Box 21: (Box 21)
    - 1st Trimester 1995 Advertising, Europe 1995 July 18 (Box 21)
    - Client Group Meeting, Chicago 1998 Sept. 16: International Spots (Box 21)
    - International Reel, 1997 Dec. (Box 21)
    - Portugal Blue and Green Wave, 1998 Apr. 1 (Box 21)
    - J. Walter Thompson Manchester: Creative Reel, 1998 Sept. (Box 21)
  - Contents of Box 22: (Box 22)
    - Worldwide Executive Group London, 1997 July 9 (Box 22)
    - International Compilation, Reel for Chris Jones, 1997 Apr. (Box 22)
    - Board of Directors: JWT Europe and Asia Pacific, The Best of 1994 1994 Nov. 17 (Box 22)
    - WWOG Reel #2, 1994 June 6-8 (Box 22)
    - The Best Commercials of Latin America (Box 22)
    - Allen T. Compilation Multinational Reel, 1996 May (Box 22)
  - Contents of Box 23: (Box 23)
    - Amusements, Leisure, and Travel (Parts 1 and 2), 1983 Jan. (Box 23)
    - Sections 2-5, 7 and 12, 1983 Jan. (Box 23)
  - Contents of Box 24: (Box 24)
    - Sections 8-11, 1983 Jan. (Box 24)
    - Amusements, Leisure, and Travel (Part 1), 1983 Feb. (Box 24)
    - Sections 2-5 and 8, 1983 Feb. (Box 24)
  - Contents of Box 25: (Box 25)
    - Sections 1, 6, 7, and 9-12, 1983 Feb. (Box 25)
    - Financial and Business Services, 1983 Jan. (Box 25)
    - J. Walter Thompson International Spots, 1995 Feb. (Box 25)
    - JWT Europe, Middle East, and Africa (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Oversize Material (Box Oversize 19)